Hello! Welcome to another episode of Bug
Bounty Eeports Explained.
Today, I will show you how Tom Van Goethem
was able to leak parts of undisclosed
Hackerone reports by using a novel
method of cross-site leaks.
Make sure to watch the video
until the end, because I will show
the outstanding trick, which
he used to have a little bit of control
over TCP protocol from the browser.
Links to the report
and to his media are in the description.
Enjoy! On Hackerone,
there is a /bugs.json endpoint.
It's used under the hood
when you use the search feature on inbox.
It has text_query parameter,
which you can use to query all the bugs
to which you have access
to as a reporter, triager or whoever else.
The endpoint used the GET method
and no CSRF protection.
As the attacker,
you were able to send requests
to this endpoint
if a victim visited your website.
Same origin policy would allow you
to query reports to which the victim
had access to and cookies
would be attached to the request.
However, same origin policy
would not allow you to read the response,
so you can't actually disclose
report contents this way.
But there are methods to exfiltrate data
in such a scenario.
Those attacks are called cross-site leaks.
The most common approach
is looking at the timing.
It works this way: the victim visits
your website, your JavaScript, sends
two requests, one with searching a string
that will never be present in any report.
The other one with a string
that you want to confirm
if it's inside an undisclosed report
to which the victim has access.
When one response will return your results
while the other will not,
the processing time of the one with
reports will be longer.
You can measure the response
time of each request,
even if you can't read
the response itself.
So if one was longer than the other,
you know the string is present
somewhere in the undisclosed report.
If both responses
had roughly the same time,
that means your string is not present
in any of the reports.
This way, you could brute force parts of
reports contents, one character at a time.
But it's not as easy as I made it look.
Differences in the time that the server
will take to process
such a simple operation are measured
in microseconds or even in nanoseconds.
Considering that the network delay
is order of magnitude
higher, in milliseconds, the difference
from a single request
doesn't mean anything.
However, when you send many parts
of such requests,
you can measure averages
and come up with significant differences.
Behind this report, there's
a bigger reseach regarding these attacks.
Researchers determined that depending
on the network location and processing
time, you must send hundreds
or thousands of requests to get
meaningful averages, which will tell you
if you did leak something or not.
And that's only to tell
if one character is in one position.
You'd have to send thousands of requests
to tell if A is the next character,
then thousands of requests to tell
if B is the next character and so on.
Exfiltrating even a short
token would require millions of requests.
And this is a client-site attack.
So the victim would have to
stay on your website for this whole time,
not to even mention
rate limits on Hackerone.
So the time attack wouldn't work here.
Take a look at that from this perspective.
You send two requests
and the time difference
you're interested in
is here, on the server.
But the place you try
to measure it is here.
Many routers and switches away.
But it has to be that way.
You can't measure the time
directly on the server.
But actually, you are not interested
in the time it took.
You are interested
in which of these two took longer?
Researchers idea was to see which of these
two responses would come back earlier.
So the hunter would send two requests.
When both where it would yield no results,
there was about 50 percent chance response
1 would come back after response 2.
However, when request
one would return a bug,
there was about 80 percent chance
it would come back second.
This still doesn't allow you to determine
the character after one pair of requests,
but this time, instead of hundreds
or thousands, 20 requests was enough.
And your location
or your connection didn't matter.
For that to work, he would have to lock
the order of responses at this point
to make sure it's
not affected on the road home.
Let me show you how he achieved it.
HTTP requests are transmitted
in TCP packets.
You can think of it as the letters.
The HTTP request is the letter itself
and TCP packet in the envelope.
If your letter is long,
it will be sent in multiple envelopes.
But if you have two short
letters to the same address,
you can send both of them
in a single envelope.
So what do you need to do
is to bundle both HTTP
requests in a single TCP packet.
In case of an attack against the server,
without the client interaction,
this is easy-peasy
because you can write a low level
script that will do whatever you want.
But in this attack, we are in the browser
and we have little control over low level
network protocols.
How do you then force the browser
to send both letters in a single envelope?
The browser has built in mechanism
to prevent sending too many envelopes
before the server acknowledges
that they were received.
So the server will send as many envelopes
as it can and the rest will be stored
in the queue, waiting for the server
to acknowledge receiving
those sent envelopes.
Normally, the browser would envelope
the first HTTP request straight away
without waiting for the second one.
But when your two letters will be queued,
they will be packed in a single envelope,
which is exactly what we need.
But how do you force the browser
to queue your requests?
By sending a big HTTP request first,
which will be too big
to be sent in one go.
Part of the request will be sent,
but the remaining packets will be queued.
Immediately after you send
your pair of requests.
One with the baseline query and the one
with the query you are interested in.
Both of them will be added
to the end of the queue.
After the sender acknowledges,
that it received
the first batch of packets, ones from
the queue will be sent
and your pair of HTTP requests
will be bundled into a one TCP packet.
Then you repeat the operation 20 times
and you look how often the response with
the query was second.
If it was second
in about half of requests,
your query did not return any reports.
If it was second in about 16 requests,
that means that the string
you are looking for is present
in at least one of the victims reports.
You can move on to the next character
or the next word.
This way, it was possible to exfiltrate
parts of private reports from Hackerone.
Still, even this optimized
technique requires a lot of requests.
The reporter estimated about 1,5 to 3,5
minutes per character,
assuming you know the first two.
This way, you could target, for example,
authorization headers,
some endpoints, specific vulnerability
classes or whatever comes to your mind.
But whatever you chose, the attack
would still probably take a few hours.
So by no means this is a high risk bug
but Hackerone staff
wrote in the comments
that there were about 8 reports
about this behavior,
and this was the first one
that presented a feasible attack.
Hence, this one was awarded $2,500.
As for the fix, the /bugs.json endpoint
now uses the POST method and thus,
it requires a CSRF token,
making this attack impossible.
And that's it. I'm always a bit sad
when the complex bug doesn't
have the critical impact.
But anyway, I learned a lot while
studying this report, and I hope you, too.
If you did make sure to feed the YouTube
algorithm with a like
so that it recommends
the video to other hackers.
I also encourage you
to watch the whole presentation about this
timeless technique
where you can also find Wi-Fi attacks.
The video is on the card right now.
For now, thank you
for watching and goodbye.